plimoth.org 2006-06-23

# Privacy Policy - Plimoth Plantation

****

Privacy Policy

Plimoth Plantation Inc. ("PP") is committed to protecting the privacy of all our online guests. We promise not to collect personally-identifiable information, such as names, postal addresses, email addresses, or credit card numbers, except when the individuals involved knowingly provide such information to us. This privacy policy outlines how PP collects and uses the information that is knowingly provided to us. PP, as well as anyone visiting or using the PP website, or communicating with PP via email, is governed by this policy.

**Online Museum Shop Purchases:**

PP may ask you to provide personally-identifiable information as necessary to fulfill your online museum shop purchase(s). This may include, but is not limited to, your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, and credit card number. You also may be asked for your email address so that we can confirm your order or communicate with you regarding processing or shipping difficulties. Your email address will not be shared, sold, or exchanged with any other company. A secure server protects your credit card information. PP will retain your personally-identifiable information for our records so that we can provide you with better customer service. From time to time, you may also receive information about special events or promotional offers, unless you "unsubscribe" to our email newsletter list, as described in "Emails and Newsletters" below.

**Online Ticket Purchases:**

PP may ask you to provide personally-identifiable information as necessary to fulfill your online ticket booth purchase(s). This may include, but is not limited to, your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, and credit card number. You also may be asked for your email address so that we can confirm your order or communicate with you regarding processing or shipping difficulties. Your email address will not be shared, sold, or exchanged with any other company. A secure server protects your credit card information. PP will retain your personally-identifiable information for our records so that we can provide you with better customer service. From time to time, you may also receive information about special events or promotional offers, unless you "unsubscribe" to our email newsletter list, as described in "Emails and Newsletters" below.

**Online Donations:**

PP may ask you to provide personally-identifiable information as necessary to process and service your online donation. This may include, but is not limited to, your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, and credit card number. You also may be asked for your email address to confirm and/or acknowledge your donation and to allow us to communicate with you if there are processing difficulties. Your email address will not be shared, sold, or exchanged with any other company. A secure server protects your credit card information. PP will retain your personally-identifiable information for our records. From time to time, you may also receive information about special events or promotional offers, unless you "unsubscribe" to our email newsletter list, as described in "Emails and Newsletters" below.

**Online Membership Purchases:**

PP may ask you to provide personally-identifiable information as necessary to process and service your online membership purchase. This may include (but is not limited to) your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, and credit card number. You also may be asked for your email address to confirm your order and to allow us to communicate with you if there are processing difficulties. Your email address will not be shared, sold, or exchanged with any other company. A secure server protects your credit card information. PP will retain your personally-identifiable information for our records and so that we can provide you with better customer service. From time to time, you may also receive information about special events or promotional offers, unless you "unsubscribe" to our email newsletter list, as described in "Emails and Newsletters" below.

**Online Surveys:**

On occasion, PP may post visitor surveys on its website. These are completely voluntary in nature. If you choose to participate, you may do so anonymously unless otherwise indicated. The information gathered from these surveys is used by PP to better understand our visitorsÍ interests and needs. It is never sold, rented, or shared with any third party for any reason.

**Information Collected Automatically:**

PP collects information related to website usage (e.g., the website pages frequently visited by our guests). This information is collected automatically for the sole purpose of analyzing our websiteÍs usage patterns, and is not shared with or sold to any third parties for any reason.

**Emails and Newsletters:**

PP occasionally sends special email newsletters to registered visitors, members, donors, and friends. These notify you of upcoming programs, special events, news, and promotional offers. Anyone may subscribe or unsubscribe to the newsletter at any time. You may register to receive email newsletters by filling out the "First to Know" pop-up box on our website. Instructions for unsubscribing are found at the end of every email communication that is sent out to you by PP.

PP tries to respond to email messages that are sent by visitors in a timely fashion. Email inquiries regarding online transactions of any kind (museum shop, ticket, membership, donations) are confidential and are forwarded to the appropriate department within PP. PP may save this information for its records, and to serve you better in the future. The content of any messages sent to PP that do not relate to an online transaction are considered non-confidential and non-proprietary.

**Data Security:**

All of the transactions that take place over the PP website are protected by a secure server. PP makes every reasonable effort to ensure that all sensitive financial data is used correctly and accurately. PP has put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and administrative procedures to safeguard all the information we collect online.

**Third Party Service Providers** :

In order to help us serve our visitors better, PP may contract with third-party vendors. PP requires all such third-party vendors to maintain the confidentiality and security of the personally-identifiable information they are supplied with in order to complete a transaction. These vendors are prohibited from using this information in any way not authorized by PP.

**Contact Information:**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact:

Plimoth Plantation, Inc.  
PO Box 1620  
Plymouth, MA 02362  
Attn: Web Content Manager  
Email: [webmaster@plimoth.org](mailto:webrequests@plimoth.org)  
Tel: (508) 746-1622, extension 8101

**Revisions to Privacy Policy:  
**This Privacy Policy may be revised from time to time; please visit this page often to ensure that you are aware of any changes.

Last updated: June 1, 2003
